He wasn't much of a man... Now he's not much of an animal!
The Animal is a comedy, science fiction film directed by Luke Greenfield.
When loser Marvin Mange is involved in a horrible car accident, he's brought
back to life by a deranged scientist as half man and half animal.
His newfound powers are awesome -- but their adverse
side effects could take over his life.
Now, Marvin must fight to control his crazy primal urges around
his new squeeze, Rianna, and his rival, Sgt.
Sisk, who both think he's one cool cat.
Marvin Mange, played by Rob Schneider.
Rianna, played by Colleen Haskell.
Sgt. Sisk, played by John C. McGinley.
Chief Wilson, played by Ed Asner.
Dr. Wilder, played by Michael Caton.
Fatty, played by Louis Lombardi.
The Animal is a 2001 American comedy film directed by Luke Greenfield, written
by Tom Brady and Rob Schneider from a story conceived by Brady.
It stars Schneider in the lead role, alongside Colleen Haskell, John C.
McGinley, Guy Torry, and Edward Asner with supporting
roles by Michael Caton and Louis Lombardi.
The film depicts a police station evidence clerk who is critically injured and is put back together by a mad
scientist who transplants animal parts, resulting in strange animalistic changes to his behavior.
Produced by Revolution Studios and Adam Sandler's production company Happy Madison Productions,
The Animal was released by Columbia Pictures in the United States on June 1, 2001.
The film received unfavorable reviews.
The film explores themes of dreams, employee, car
crash, scientist, police officer.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.